Finding Aid for University of Michigan Club of Washington, D.C. records, 1935-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
University of Michigan Club of Washington, D.C. records 1935-1985
University of Michigan Club of Washington, D.C.
1.5 linear feet
861144 Bimu H1a 2
Correspondence of club secretary-treasurer T. Maxwell Collier relating to club functions, dinners and reunions; also mailings, minutes, newsletters, press releases, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by T. Maxwell Collier (Donor No. 3267 ) in November 1989.
No further additions to the records expected.
The records are open for research.
Theodore Maxwell Collier was born on June 28, 1909, and spent his youth in Frankfort, Michigan, graduating from Frankfort High School in 1927. He received his B.A. from the University of Michigan in 1931 and his M.A. in 1932. He was employed as an archivist by the Memorial Division of the U.S. Army for over thirty years, beginning in 1936. Mr. Collier had a longtime association with the University of Michigan Alumni Club of Washington, D.C., which he served as secretary/treasurer from 1942 to 1962. He also served for some time as secretary/treasurer of the Second District of the Alumni Association (of which the Washington Club was one member). In addition, Mr. Collier was involved with the Michigan State Society, an organization of people in the Washington, D.C. area who have an affiliation with the state of Michigan. He served this group as historian, and wrote an organizational history on the occasion of its centennial in 1962.
The collection is divided into five series: Papers, Topical File, Correspondence, Photographs and Sound Recordings. The papers series (1 linear foot) consists of minutes, reports, incoming and outgoing correspondence of the secretary/treasurer, copies of the club president's correspondence, and correspondence from the secretary of the Alumni Association. Although the items date from 1924 to 1985, most of the material covers the 1950s, when Mr. Collier was most active. The papers were received in considerable disarray, and were rearranged chronologically. The topical files were retained in their original form. Some overlap may exist between the two types of files. The Correspondence series is largely of copies of correspondence from Alumni Association General Director T. Hawley Tapping to alumni and others in the Washington D.C. area and correspondence with representatives of other U-M alumni clubs. The Photographs series consists of prints from the Congressional Dinner hosted by the club. The audiotapes include talks by U-M President Robben Fleming and Gerald Ford at the club's annual dinner.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae--Washington (D.C.); University of Michigan Club of Washington, D.C.; Collier, T. Maxwell.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
University of Michigan Club of Washington, D.C.
Contributors- Sound Rrecordings:
Fleming, R. W. (Robben Wright), 1916-; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Papers
  - 1938-1943 (Box 1)
  - 1945-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950 (Box 1)
  - 1951 (Box 1)
  - 1952, 2 Folders (Box 1)
  - 1953, 2 Folders (Box 1)
  - 1954, 2 Folders (Box 1)
  - 1955, 2 Folders (Box 1)
  - 1956, 2 Folders (Box 1)
  - 1957 (Box 1)
  - 1958 (Box 1)
  - 1959 (Box 1)
  - 1960-1962 (Box 1)
  - 1963-1969 (Box 1)
  - 1974-1985 (Box 1)
- Topical Files
  - U of M Alumni Assn, Second District (Box 1)
  - Alumni Club Scholarships (Box 1)
  - Alumni Dinner, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Congressional Dinners, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - Honor Awards, 1949-1952 (Box 1)
  - Howell Scholarship, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Membership, 1946-1948 (Box 1)
  - Membership lists, 1952-1957 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, March 1951-February 1956 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - 1950-1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 1)
  - Press Releases, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
  - Promotional Materials
    - 1950-1955 (Box 1)
    - 1955-1960 (Box 1)
- Papers and Correspondence
  - 1943-1948 (Box 2)
  - 1948 (Box 2)
  - 1949-1953 (Box 2)
  - 1943-1947 (outgoing) (Box 2)
  - 1948-1949 (outgoing) (Box 2)
  - 1948-1940 (Box 2)
    (copies of T. Hawley Tapping correspondence to Washington, D.C. area alumni)
- Photographs
  - Congressional Dinner
    - 1957 (Box 2)
    - 1958 (Box 2)
    - 1960 (Box 2)
- Sound recordings
  - 1975 Annual Dinner (Box 2)
    (Gerald Ford spoke)
  - 1976 Annual Dinner (Box 2)
    (Robben Fleming spoke)